# MAHEDI KAISER

http://mahedikaiser.com mahedi.kaiser@gmail.com 347.925.4458

### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with over 5 years of experience and a track record for optimizing business processes through automation and innovation. Experience working in corporate and startup environments. Performed all roles in development including front-end, back-end, deployment/server management, and interfacing with business. A highly adaptable, passionate learner with a strong work ethic.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer New York, NY September 2018 – March 2019

Bombfell (Startup)

Payment System Rewrite (September 2018 – March 2019)

- Saved the company an average of 10% per refund transaction by fixing loophole in refund process
- Eliminated technical debt from payment system by refactoring and modularizing code
- Made payment system more robust and maintainable by implementing test framework

Pagespeed Optimization (February 2019 – March 2019)

- Improved load time and search ranking by increasing Google Pagespeed score by 70 points (out of 100)
- Optimized Webpack resource loading using commons chunks and compression plugins
- Reorganized page structure and lazy-loaded below-the-fold contents

Security & Authentication (December 2018 – February 2019)

- Implemented Multi-factor Authentication for internal accounts
- Made accounts more brute-force resistant by implementing bcrypt password hashing
- Added feature to allow managers to enable/disable compromised accounts

Bombfell Shop Launch (September 2018 – December 2018)

- Coordinated with Product Manager, Stylists, and 4 other developers to launch ecommerce shop in 2 months
- Wrote Server side code to search, sort, and cache shop items based on various filters and user preferences
- Developed multiple React components for Shop UI

Software Engineer Detroit, MI June 2016 – September 2018
General Motors

Salesforce Rewrite Project (January 2018 – April 2018)

- Rewrote Salesforce APIs as in-house microservices to extend availability of services to more regions globally
- Collaborated with a team of 15 developers and architects to make microservices work together seamlessly
- Wrote comprehensive unit tests & integration tests to ensure code reliability and maintainability

Data Setup & Diagnostics Tool (February 2017 – September 2018)

- Cut defect resolution and data setup times by 30% by identifying bottlenecks in the process and creating a Web UI to circumvent said bottlenecks
- Collaborated with a single teammate to design, develop & deploy the tool in under 6 months
- Minimized page load times by implementing Elasticsearch pipeline
- Used AJAX and wrote AngularJS plugins to provide fast, smooth, and intuitive user experience

Test Automation (June 2016 – September 2018)

- Responsible for creating automated tests for new Salesforce REST APIs using JUnit & Jenkins
- Improved readability and business utility of unit test results by migrating to Cucumber
- Minimized build failures by collaborating across multiple teams to resolve defects

### **SKILLS**

Web Development ReactJS, AngularJS, NodeJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, WordPress, Weblogic, Webpack,

HTML, SASS, CSS

**Programming Languages** Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

Frameworks & Technologies Springboot, SQLAlchemy, Elasticsearch, Linux, JUnit, Cucumber Tools Git, SVN, VIM, Eclipse, Intellij, Android Studios, Jenkins, Postman

Operating Systems Windows, Linux, Mac OSX

# MAHEDI KAISER

http://mahedikaiser.com mahedi.kaiser@gmail.com 347.925.4458

#### **EDUCATION**

Lehman College | BSc: Computer Science | GPA: 3.8

Dean's List (Fall 2014 – Spring 2015)

Class of June 2016

#### **ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES**

**Founder & Instructor** 

Bronx, NY

January 2019 – Present

**Fullstack Engineering Bootcamp** 

 Developed and taught a comprehensive curriculum for fullstack development at my local community center aimed at anyone interested in learning software engineering

Mentored a wide range of students ranging from high school to post-college

**Academic Excellence Chair** 

Bronx, NY

January 2016 - March 2016

**National Society of Black Engineers** 

Organized workshops and study groups for computer science classes offered by Lehman college

Hosted resume reviews and interview preparation workshops for students seeking jobs and internships

**2<sup>nd</sup> Place Winner** Boston, MA March 2016

**National Google Hackathon** 

• Worked with a team of 5 to create an android app to help drive up adoption rates by connecting prospective adopters with foster care children

1<sup>st</sup> Place Winner Bronx, NY October 2015

**State-Wide NSBE Hackathon** 

• Worked with a team of 5 to create a mobile & web solution to connect people who need to give away their pets with prospective adopters with the purpose of keeping them out of kill shelters

• Independently developed a web app for the project using JavaScript to dynamically filter & display search results in addition to a second webpage to serve as a demo for the application

**Mathematics Researcher & Programmer** 

Bronx, NY

October 2015 – January 2016

**CUNY- Research Foundation** 

- Worked in groups to come up with algorithms to compute shortest paths in CAT(k) space with direct application to mapping optimal evolutionary history in phylogenetic trees
- Wrote Python code to implement proposed solutions